Guide to the Philip Wagner papers, (ca. 1934-1997)
Wagner, Philip papers, (ca. 1934-1997)
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Philip Wagner papers, (ca. 1934-1997)
6928
Philip Wagner, 1904-1996
10.2 cubic ft.
Daybooks, correspondence, notes, research materials, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Daybooks, correspondence, notes, research materials, photographs relating to family and vineyard business travel in U.S. and Europe, and business records of the Boordy Vineyard and Nursery in Maryland..
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Philip Wagner was born in New Haven, Connecticut in 1904, and grew up in Ann Arbor, Michigan, where his father was Professor of Romance languages at the University of Michigan. He received an A.B. degree from the University of Michigan in 1925, and worked in the publicity department of the General Electric Company in Schenectady, New York, from 1925 to 1930. In 1930 he moved to Baltimore, Maryland, where he began work at the Baltimore Sun newspapers. He was editorial writer for The Sun 1930-1936, London correspondent for The Sun 1936-1937, editor of the editorial page of The Evening Sun until 1943, then The Sun until 1964.
His interest in grapes and winemaking is evident in a photograph circa 1910 showing him attempting to work a basket press. He became seriously involved in vineyard cultivation and winemaking after moving to Baltimore during Prohibition. In 1932 he rented a property in Riderwood, Maryland that had the remains of a twenty vine vineyard. After working on the vineyard for a year, he purchased the property and planted his first vines. In 1933, his first book, American Wines and How to Make Them was published, and it was at the time the only available book on the subject in English. For a few years he experimented with grape varieties, and while on assignment in London he discovered the French hybrids during a visit to an agricultural station in East Malling. This led to his importing vines from Maurice Baco in 1938, which in turn led to the nursery that supplied stock for the thousands of Baco vines in the East today.
In 1940, he and Jocelyn McDonough were married and formed a lifetime partnership, "J. and P. Wagner, Props.," subsequently expanding the Boordy Vineyard and establishing the Boordy Winery, the cornerstone for which was laid in 1943. In 1945, he published A Wine-Growers Guide. This volume became a crucial reference for grape growers in the East. Philip and Jocelyn traveled extensively to the wine growing regions of France, Spain, Italy, Portugal, Yugoslavia, and Russia in their search for disease-resistant varieties of grapes that would also be suited for cooler climates. After thirty-five years the winery was sold in 1980, but until 1994 Philip and Jocelyn operated the vineyard, selling vines and supplies to private individuals and business concerns before their health became too poor to continue. Philip Wagner died in 1996.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The Philip Wagner papers consist of correspondence, photographs and negatives, manuscripts, an obituary, clippings, subject files, nursery, viticulture and wine making records, notebooks, order books, logbooks, and other material relating to Wagner's career as a winemaker, grapegrower, and cultivator of new varieties of grapes. Correspondence with other growers and winemakers shows the operation of the Boordy Vineyard and reveals Wagner's standing in the industry. Also included in the correspondence is documentation of dealings with the interstate liquor licensing boards in Texas and Pennsylvania, and lading slips from shippers.
Vintage records include logbooks for each season, nursery and supply records, transaction records with individuals and privately owned vineyards and wineries from widely varying regions of the U. S. including Maryland, New England, New York's Finger Lakes Region, the Midwest, Texas, and California, and some reports of experimentation during the establishment of these enterprises. There is correspondence with agriculture departments in Maryland, New York, New Hampshire, Arkansas, Missouri, Minnesota, Wisconsin, and California. Business records include sales book receipts for vine and non-vine supplies.
New York State wineries included in the correspondence are: Amberg Nursery and Winery, Clifton Springs; Brimstone Hill Vineyard, Pine Bush, and Lucas Vineyards, Interlaken; Bully Hill, Pleasant Valley, Taylor, and Urbana Wineries, Hammondsport.
Photographs and slides include scenery of many vineyards and winery operations from the Wagners' trips in the United States and abroad. Also included are many images of family and friends.
The final section includes newspaper columns from Philip's assignment to London in 1936-37.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Einset, John, 1915-; Olmo, H. P. (Harold Paul), 1909-2006; Watson, John P.; Wagner, Philip, 1904-1996.; Boordy Vineyard.
Subjects:
Wine and wine making--Maryland.; Grapes--Varieties.; Viticulture.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Biographical
Box 1
Series II. Correspondence: Professional and Personal A-Z
Boxes 1-8
Series III. Vintage Records
Boxes 8-9
Series IV. Business Receipt Books
Boxes 9-10
Series V. Photographs
Boxes 11-16
Series VI. Newspaper Columns
Box 17
Series VII. Miscellaneous Publications
Box 18
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Biographical
  - Obituary (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - Correspondence: Professional and Personal A-Z
    - A Miscellaneous, 1965-75 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - A Miscellaneous, 1976-93 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Acidity - Reduction, 1967, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Alcohol - Abuse/Benefits, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Amerine, Maynard Andrew, 1961-86 (Box 1, Folder 6-8)
    - Amerine, Maynard Andrew, 1986-96 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
    - ACS [American Chemical Society] Paper, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Association of American Vintners, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Azrel, Louis, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - ACS Paper - Final Draft, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - American Fruit Grower, 1987-91 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - ASE [American Society of Enologists], 1981-88 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - AWS [American Wine Society] Journal, 1987-92 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - AWS Meeting - Alexander, 1977, 1977-78 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - AWS Meeting - Baltimore, 1986, 1974-86 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Aramon - Maroger, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Asbestos, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - B Miscellaneous, 1956-91 (Box 1, Folder 22-5)
    - No Title (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - BAFT, 1977-84 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Bobby [Robinson], 1983-93 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Boordy - resale, 1978-80 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Beards, James - Baltimore Visit, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Baco #1 - Importation of 1st wines, 1938-39 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Black, Harry C., 1956 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - C Miscellaneous, 1955-64 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - C Miscellaneous, 1972-92 (Box 1, Folder 34-35)
    - California - Food and Civilization, 1963-64 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - California, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - California - Lectureship, 1954-61 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Charlettesville, 1936-81 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Canton [Ohio], ca.1960 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Cheek, Leslie, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Cooperage, 1946-78 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Cooperage (Tchelistcheff), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Cork, 1963-87 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Crown Gall (including Goodman), 1977-79 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Country Life, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - D Miscellaneous, 1951-89 (Box 1, Folder 47-48)
    - Dressler, 1983-87 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Donations, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Didglucosides, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - De Chaunac, 1952-68 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Dujardin, 1965-74 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - E Miscellaneous, 1965-84 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Ewald, Helen, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Ewald, Helen - also Ruth [Mrs. Elvin R. Latty], 1981-88 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Entomology - Cask borers and spray information, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - [Eastern Grape Growers and Winery News] Vineyard & Winery Management, 1983-88 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Europe, 1966-70 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Europe - Spain, Mallorca, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Europe - Bordeaux, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - F Miscellaneous, 1962-90 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Fan Mail, 1971-78 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Fetal Alcohol Syndrome - also cancer stuff, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Finger Lakes Paper: Eastern Wine Growing Potential - also Botanists, 1972-73 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Fournier, Charles [Gold Seal Vineyards], 1955-83 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - F.T.C., 1952-92 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - French Correspondence, 1942-62 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Fungicides, 1976-77 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - G Miscellaneous, 1964-95 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
    - Geneva, 1972, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Gale, George - China, 1984-86 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Grafting, 1963-95 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Guttmacher, 1951-93 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - H Miscellaneous, 1943-94 (Box 2, Folder 23-24)
    - Hamilton Street Club, 1988-91 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Hybrids - Papers, 1948-78 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - I Miscellaneous, 1965-78 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Ingredient Labeling, 1979-81 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - J Miscellaneous, 1951-87 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - K Miscellaneous, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Knopf, Alfred A. - Judith Jones and others, 1945-95 (Box 2, Folder 31-34)
    - L Miscellaneous, 1963-94 (Box 2, Folder 35-37)
    - Lippmann, 1963-65 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - M Miscellaneous, 1952-93 (Box 2, Folder 39-43)
    - Maclet-Botton, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Map Project - Maryland, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Maceration carbonicue, 1984-86 (Box 2, Folder 46-47)
    - Marot - Fenavino, 1937-73 (Box 2, Folder 48-49)
    - MGGA [Maryland Grape Growers Association], 1985-91 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - MGGA - Talk 1990 (White Wine Hybrids), 1990-91 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Moncrieff, 1979-88 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Morton, Lucie, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Munson, T. V, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Medical - Mycosa, 1982-84 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Mencken, Hollins Street Restoration, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - McGrew, 1978-79 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - N Miscellaneous, 1964-93 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Neo-Prohibition, 1989-90 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - New York Horticultural Society, 1964-82 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - New York State - Geneva - Soil Analysis, 1972-93 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Nursery Advertising, 1975-92 (Box 3, Folder 8--9)
    - New York Experimental Station, 1965-70 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - O Miscellaneous, 1963-92 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Oak - Cooperage, 1934-72 (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
    - Olmo, Harold P., 1962-76 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Overseas Writers, 1959-65 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Owens, J. Hamilton - Funeral, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Ozark - Dressel [Lucian]- includes Navel orange, Rubber trees, 1985-86 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - P Miscellaneous, 1962-82 (Box 3, Folder 18-20)
    - Penn State Wine Meeting, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Penn State Wine Meeting, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Penn State Wine Meeting, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Phylloxera, 1957-61 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - E. Peynard (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Pittsburgh Academy of Medicine, 1978-79 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Pokomoke River, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Promotion - Distributers, 1952-88 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Promotion - Book, 1974-76 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Prosser [Washington], 1965-73 (Box 3, Folder 30-32)
    - Publicity, 1953-95 (Box 3, Folder 33-39)
    - Publicity - Mailing List, 1983-91 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Publicity - Advertising, 1952-72 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Publicity - Wine List and Growing Instructions (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - R Miscellaneous, 1964-88 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Rigg, Sally, 1971-89 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Rubber stamps, old labels, promotion (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - S Miscellaneous, 1979-92 (Box 4, Folder 04-6)
    - Schoonmaker, Frank, 1947-76 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Scientific American - Freeman, 1970-83 (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
    - Seneca - Art - Post Termination, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Seneca - Critical, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Seneca - termination - also, Distributor List, 1976-78 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Serendipity Cellars, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Sotheby Book - Climate Chapter, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 14-15)
    - Sotheby Book - MAA Chapter 8[?], 1982 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Sotheby Book - MAA 1st draft, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Sotheby book - Climate-MAA/PW Mss of Both, as editied by PW, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 18-19)
    - Stag's Leap, 1987-88 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - T Miscellaneous, 1944-88 (Box 4, Folder 21-23)
    - Texas Grape Growers, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Tri-Bio-Wine Lab, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Turner - Book of Wines, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - U Miscellaneous, 1967-92 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - USDA Yearbook, 1976-77 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - V Miscellaneous, 1978-86 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Vineland [Vineland Station, Ontario], 1965-66 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Virginia Talk, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Virus, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - W Miscellaneous, 1966-89 (Box 4, Folder 33-34)
    - Wagner, Charles P., 19947-64 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Wagner, P - Will, etc., 1944-75 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Wagner, Philip - personal, 1952-64 (Box 4, Folder 37-39)
    - Wagner, Robert, 1955-71 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Wagner, Sue, 1983-89 (Box 4, Folder 41-42)
    - Wellington, Richard, 1961-68 (Box 4, Folder 43)
      Includes photocopies transfered from NYSAES and a letter from Joseph Mathias to Wellington regarding Wagner.
    - Wine Book, 1959-65 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Wine East - Cattell, 1988-94 (Box 4, Folder 45-46)
    - Wine Institute, 1974-75 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Wineries Unlimited, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Wines and Vines, 1981-89 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Wolcott, 1985-91 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - W Miscellaneous, 1976-90 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Yardley (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Yardley (copies), 1951-79 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Z Miscellaneous, 1978-82 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Philip Wagner Miscellaneous 1962-1967 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Donald Tyerman 1962-1963 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Nursery [Grape and Wine]
    - A Miscellaneous, 1961-95 (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
    - Amurensis - Cold Hardy Hybrids, 1982-86 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - B Miscellaneous, 1944-95 (Box 5, Folder 5-8)
    - Boordy's, 1944-95 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Boordy Nursery Books (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Book - New Wine Book surplus photos, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - British Columbia (selling, etc.), 1979-92 (Box 5, Folder 12-13)
    - C Miscellneous, 1971-96 (Box 5, Folder 14-17)
    - Clippings, 1967-94 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Concord Nursery, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - D Miscellaneous, 1973-92 (Box 5, Folder 20-21)
    - E Miscellaneous, 1979-91 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Experimenters - Vines: Bell-Gage-Pugliese-Bailly, 1964-86 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - F Miscellaneous, 1963-95 (Box 5, Folder 24-26)
    - G Miscellaneous, 1949-94 (Box 5, Folder 27-29)
    - H Miscellaneous, 1939-95 (Box 5, Folder 30-32)
    - Husfeld, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - I Miscellaneous, 1972-93 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - J Miscellaneous, 1977-93 (Box 5, Folder 35-36)
    - K Miscellaneous, 1974-93 (Box 5, Folder 37-38)
    - L Miscellaneous, 1971-93 (Box 5, Folder 39-41)
    - M Miscellaneous, 1973-93 (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
    - Mc Miscellaneous, 1975-94 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - N Miscellaneous, 1942-95 (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
    - O Miscellaneous, 1956-93 (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
    - P Miscellaneous, 1963-93 (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
    - Q Miscellaneous, 1965-81 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - R Miscellaneous, 1963-92 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - S Miscellaneous, 1958-92 (Box 6, Folder 14-19)
    - T Miscellaneous, 1960-92 (Box 6, Folder 20-22)
    - U Miscellaneous, 1941-82 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - USDA, 1965-90 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - V Miscellaneous, 1963-94 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Vineland, Ont. - Fisher, 1977-86 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - W Miscellaneous, 1965-93 (Box 6, Folder 27-28)
    - Wagner Family, 1961-92 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Wine, 1976-95 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Winter Hardening, 1975-82 (Box 6, Folder 31-33)
    - Y Miscellaneous, 1968-93 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Z Miscellaneous, 1976-92 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Plat - Plan, etc. Permits, 1945-68 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
    - Miscellaneous Documents - Forms 698, Plats, etc., 1953-71 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Nursery, 1974-77 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Vineyard Charts, 1977-92 (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
    - Bountiful Ridge, 1978-79 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Nursery, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Nursery, 1979-80 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Barboursville Corp., 1978-79 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Nursery, 1980-81 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Nursery, 1981-82 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Nursery, 1982-83 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Nursery, 1983-84 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Nursery, 1984-85 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Nursery, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Nursery, 1987-88 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Nursery, 1988-89 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Nursery, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Nursery, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Nursery, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Nursery - General, 1984-92 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Nursery - Postal, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Concord Nursery, 1992-93 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Nursery, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Nursery - Paid, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Nursery - Postage, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Nursery -Licensing, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Nursery, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Boordy Vineyards - Accessions/Descriptions, 1982-92 (Box 8, Folder 12-13)
    - Orders, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Orders, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Orders, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Orders, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Orders, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Vine Orders, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Series III. Vintage Records
  - Notebooks: Vintage Reviews, 1951-76 (Box 8, Folder 20-45)
  - Notebooks: Vintage Reviews, 1977-95 (Box 9, Folder 1-4)
  - Notebooks: Batch Books, 1967-74 (Box 9, Folder 5-11)
  - Envelopes: Card file of supply customers (Box 9, Folder 12-16)
  - Envelope: Index to addresses by subject (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Envelope: Appointment Book, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Series IV. Business Receipt Books
  - Order Books, 1956-93 (Box 9, Folder 19-76)
  - Order Books, 1956-93 (Box 10, Folder 1-29)
- Series V. Photographs
  Box 14 contains a metal slide box in which envelopes 33-44 are held.
  - Philip and Robert in sailor suits (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Old homestead (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Philip (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Bob, Ruthie & Philip (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Philip at typewriter, Boordy (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Philip (negatives) (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Jocelyn, 1939, 1957, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Jocelyn and Philip on the lawn, n.d. ('40's) (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Jocelyn passport photos (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Mr. Phillip Wagner & Whife [sic] (negstives), March 9, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Jocelyn and Philip at home (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Philip and Susan playing penny whistles (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Eglin Field (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Close-ups of Jocelyn (negatives), 1948 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Jocelyn and unidentified person, summer 1953 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Color transparencies, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    California Summer 1953, Forest Genetics
  - Jocelyn, Miller, Delarue, unidentified, summer 1954 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Phil's "place," Orlando, Florida, 1960's (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Phil's place in Orlando, Christmas 1961, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Phil's place in Orlando, Christmas 1961, negative of Philip on horseback, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - France, Ireledin, J in Chiblix (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Family gathering, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 17-20)
  - Family gathering, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 21-22)
  - Pony, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Seneca, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Family gathering, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Philip and Jocelyn (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Family, 1975, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Mary E. & Bill, Jenny & co. in summer, Wolcott children in Fall, Wroten Island 12/31/75 (negatives), 1975 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Unidentified, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 28-29)
    Trip western U.S.
  - Family, Susan Wagner, Walter Taylor, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 30-31)
  - Family gathering, Susan, Philip, Jocelyn (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Cats, Jocelyn, Boordy, negatives, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 33-34)
  - Family, Boordy, unidentified house (Susan's?), Jocelyn, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 35-36)
  - Christmas in Boston, Boordy, Fall 1979 (Box 11, Folder 37-41)
  - Bobby illustrating the new metal vineyard rods, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Glendalough (commercial photos) (Box 11, Folder 43-44)
  - Vineyard photos, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Christmas in Boston, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - Jocelyn, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - J[ocelyn] birthday, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Family at Boordy, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - Boordy, Philip (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - Boordy, Jocelyn (prints and negatives) (Box 11, Folder 51)
  - Sun column photo (Box 11, Folder 52)
  - Sun column photo, Sept. 1972 (Box 11, Folder 53)
  - Boordy (Box 11, Folder 54)
    exterior, interior, Philip, Jocelyn, Jocelyn filing bottles in winery
  - Boordy exterior (Box 11, Folder 55)
  - Boordy exterior, vineyard (Box 11, Folder 56)
  - Boordy exterior, delivery truck, Jocelyn and Philip with unidentified man (Box 11, Folder 57)
  - Boordy staff, unidentified building exterior (Phil's place in Orlando?) (Box 11, Folder 58)
  - Winery worker, wine judging/tasting, Boordy visitor with Jocelyn and Philip, Boordy exterior (Box 11, Folder 59)
  - Wine judging/tasting (Box 11, Folder 60)
  - Wine judging/tasting (Box 11, Folder 61)
  - Dr. K. Frank, NY (Box 11, Folder 61)
  - Al Wiedeker, AK (Box 11, Folder 61)
  - Jocelyn Wagner (Box 11, Folder 61)
  - Boordy (Box 11, Folder 62)
    negatives of Philip and Jocelyn
  - Boordy (Box 11, Folder 63)
    Jocelyn
  - Proofs (Box 11, Folder 64)
    Davis taken for Grapes into Wine but not used
  - Unidentified men (Box 11, Folder 65)
  - Gerard Marot and family on estate near Poitiers, France, August 1948 (Box 11, Folder 66)
  - First Carload Bottles, February (Box 11, Folder 67)
  - Prof. and Mrs. Turcovic, Jugoslavia, July, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 67)
  - Jwo and Haley, October 11, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 68)
  - Arthur Woods, Claremont CA, November (Box 11, Folder 69)
  - Unidentified group, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 69)
  - Jocelyn, March 1961 (Box 11, Folder 70)
  - Boordy, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 71)
    Wine judging/tasting
  - Philip (photo taken by Alfred Knopf, August 1963 (Box 11, Folder 72)
  - Boordy grape harvest, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 73)
  - Boordy exterior, two unidentified men, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 74)
  - Philip, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 75)
  - Phil Carroll - Doughovin, spring (Box 11, Folder 76)
  - Mark and Mary Miller - Benmari, June, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 76)
  - Boordy (negatives), 1976 (Box 11, Folder 77)
    Lab instruments, upstairs room, winery pictures, spring ice storm on dormant vines
  - "Negative of J[ocelyn] in waiting room on our way to Europe. One of my favorites. " Philip Wagner, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 78)
  - Leon Adams, Harold Olmo, Phil Wagner (Box 11, Folder 79)
  - Photos by Lucie Morton, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 79)
  - Jocelyn, family and friends, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 80)
  - Jocelyn and Philip, August 1978 (Box 11, Folder 81)
  - Boordy, November 1983 (Box 11, Folder 82)
    Jocelyn modelling Hotte
  - Maynard Amerine, Deferis vineyard, Minnesota, September 1985 (Box 11, Folder 83)
  - Helmut Becker and Philip "At our house after J[ocelyn]'s dinner" ("w/ Joachim Hollerin & others at dinner, our home"), Spring 1987, 1985, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 83)
  - Boordy exterior, vineyards (most in color), 1989 (Box 11, Folder 84-85)
  - Boordy nursery, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 86)